<Document>
  <ColorBox Color="#353535" OutlineColor="#555555" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Misfits: Nuclear Wasteland – Server Rules
      </Box>
      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        Misfits: Nuclear Wasteland is a Medium Roleplay Fallout server. The goal is not only engaging gameplay, but the creation of memorable stories shaped by player choice.

        The Wasteland is harsh and consequences matter. Your survival depends on your actions, your alliances, and your judgment. Administrative intervention is rare and reserved for rule enforcement, not story rescue.
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  <ColorBox Color="#2f2f3a" OutlineColor="#4f4f5a" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Rule 0: Conduct
      </Box>
      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        This is a collaborative environment. Toxicity, ego play, and behavior designed to ruin others’ enjoyment are not tolerated.

        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Play to create story, not to “win” at any cost.

          Respect administrators and developers. They are volunteers.

          Cooperate during admin interactions. Do not disconnect during an active ticket without valid reason.

          Report technical issues promptly.

          Administration may intervene in situations not explicitly covered by the rules if behavior damages the community or the round.
        </Box>

        Punishments are issued at staff discretion based on severity, context, and history.
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  <ColorBox Color="#2f3a2f" OutlineColor="#4f5a4f" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Rule 1: Griefing
      </Box>
      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        Griefing is any action taken primarily to disrupt gameplay or degrade the experience of others without meaningful in-character reasoning.

        This includes:
        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Deliberate destruction with no RP justification.

          Trap placement intended only to frustrate.

          Causing large-scale disruption without narrative basis.
        </Box>

        Lack of intent does not always excuse large-scale damage. If your actions severely impact the round without reasonable RP logic, they may be treated as griefing.
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  <ColorBox Color="#3a2f2f" OutlineColor="#5a4f4f" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Rule 2: Fair Play
      </Box>

      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        2.1 Metagaming

        Using out-of-character knowledge to influence in-character actions is prohibited.

        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Information from Discord, streams, OOC chat, or ghosting may not be used IC.

          Coordinated external communication affecting the round is forbidden.

          Streaming is allowed, but responsibility for information leaks lies with the streamer.
        </Box>

        Metagaming violations may result in removal.
      </Box>

      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        2.2 Multiaccounting

        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Using multiple accounts in the same round is forbidden.

          Ban evasion is strictly prohibited.

          Creating alternate accounts to avoid punishment history is not allowed.
        </Box>

        Violations may result in permanent bans.
      </Box>

      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        2.3 Exploits

        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          No cheats, scripts, macros, or third-party tools.

          No intentional abuse of bugs.

          No deliberate server strain.
        </Box>

        Report discovered bugs through official channels.
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  <ColorBox Color="#2f3a3a" OutlineColor="#4f5a5a" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Rule 3: Roleplay Standards
      </Box>

      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        Characters must fit the Fallout setting in tone, behavior, and naming.

        3.1 Character Identity
        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          No meme names or obvious real-world references.

          No reuse of deceased or permanently imprisoned characters without approval.

          Administration may require name changes for immersion reasons.
        </Box>

        3.2 Communication
        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Do not break immersion with mechanical terms or real-world memes.

          Keep OOC topics out of IC channels.

          OOC channels must remain respectful and free of political or extremist discussion.
        </Box>

        3.3 Atmosphere
        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Avoid referencing game systems or “admins” in character.

          Provide in-character explanations for absence when possible.

          Do not create offensive or explicit material using in-game media.
        </Box>

        3.4 Knowledge Limits
        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Your character is not all-knowing.

          Do not reference unresearched advanced technology.

          Stay within the expertise of your chosen role.
        </Box>
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  <ColorBox Color="#3a2f3a" OutlineColor="#5a4f5a" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Rule 4: Erotic Roleplay
      </Box>
      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        Explicit ERP is prohibited in all forms, including written in-game material.

        Light romantic interaction such as flirting, hugging, or kissing is allowed if non-explicit and consensual.

        If instructed by staff to stop behavior near the boundary, you must comply immediately.

        Violations may result in permanent removal.
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  <ColorBox Color="#2f3a3a" OutlineColor="#4f5a5a" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Rule 5: SSD Protection
      </Box>
      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        Characters who disconnect (SSD) may not be directly harmed.

        They may be looted, but not killed or kidnapped.

        Disconnecting during active combat or escalation removes this protection.

        SSD characters inside faction bases during active raids are not protected.
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  <ColorBox Color="#40282a" OutlineColor="#603c3f" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Rule 6: Armed Conflict
      </Box>

      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        6.1 Escalation

        Dialogue must precede lethal force in most situations.

        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Escalation must be face-to-face.

          A clear demand must be given.

          A reasonable opportunity to respond must exist.
        </Box>

        Exceptions include active firefights, immediate threats, wildlife, faction wars, and designated high-risk zones.
      </Box>

      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        6.2 Robbery

        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Do not strip victims of all survival means.

          Non-resisting victims must be left alive.

          Resistance shifts responsibility for outcome.
        </Box>
      </Box>

      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        6.3 Faction Warfare

        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Factions begin neutral.

          Only recognized leaders may formally declare war.

          War begins five minutes after a face-to-face declaration.

          Killing diplomats or surrendered individuals is forbidden.
        </Box>
      </Box>

      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        6.4 Early Raids

        Faction bases may not be raided within the first 30 minutes of the round.
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  <ColorBox Color="#3a3033" OutlineColor="#5a4a50" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Rule 7: New Life Rule
      </Box>

      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        7.1 Within a Round
        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          You may not rejoin on the same character to bypass death or punishment.

          Revived characters forget the circumstances of their death and the final moments preceding it.
        </Box>

        7.2 Between Rounds
        <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
          Do not use knowledge from previous rounds for advantage.

          Characters do not remember contradictory past events.
        </Box>
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>

  <ColorBox Color="#353535" OutlineColor="#555555" OutlineThickness="2" Margin="5">
    <Box Orientation="Vertical">
      <Box Orientation="Horizontal" HorizontalAlignment="Center">
        Administrative Authority
      </Box>
      <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="10">
        Project leadership and senior moderation retain final authority in rule interpretation.

        The server maintains a 16+ expectation.

        Rules may evolve as the project develops.
      </Box>
    </Box>
  </ColorBox>
</Document>