<Document>
# Tribes

Tribes are among the oldest post-war social structures in the Fallout universe. Long before the NCR organized a government or the Brotherhood fortified a bunker, tribal communities formed from survivors who stayed together through kinship, shared land, and shared belief. They have endured for over two centuries through deep environmental knowledge, oral tradition, and fierce community bonds.

Each tribe is shaped entirely by its Elder. The Elder's philosophy defines whether the tribe is peaceful or aggressive, isolationist or open to trade, suspicious of technology or eager to adopt it.

## Philosophy

Tribal societies place community over individual ambition and oral history over written records. They often possess environmental knowledge that outsiders entirely miss — which plants are edible, which ruins are stable, which seasonal patterns the Wasteland follows. What all tribes share is a fierce will to survive on their own terms.

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#d69b3d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Tribal Chieftan[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Chieftans in Fallout's tribal societies are the ultimate decision-makers for their people — figures like Elder Hakunin of Arroyo or the various tribal leaders encountered across New Vegas. They hold authority through wisdom and the community's trust, not military force. Unlike Brotherhood ranks, a Tribal Chieftan's power can be genuinely challenged from within if they lose their people's confidence.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Set your tribe's character for the round. Decide how your people relate to the town, the NCR, the Brotherhood, and the wider Wasteland. Your choices shape everyone beneath you — make them with intention.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#d69b3d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Tribal Warrior[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Tribal warriors are formidable despite — sometimes because of — their lack of advanced technology. Armed with melee weapons, throwing spears, and whatever they can scavenge, they compensate with tenacity, pack tactics, and intimate knowledge of their own terrain. A motivated tribal warrior fighting on home ground is not to be underestimated regardless of equipment.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Protect the tribe and enforce the Elder's will in the field. When conflict arrives — and it will — you are the tribe's first and last line of defense.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#d69b3d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Tribal Shaman[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Shamans occupy a unique position in Fallout's tribal societies — combining medical knowledge, spiritual authority, and community memory. Characters like Hakunin from Fallout 2 or the Forecaster in New Vegas capture the archetype: individuals who exist slightly outside normal social rules and whose insights — however eccentric — carry genuine weight with their community. Shamans understand plants, poisons, and the moods of the Wasteland in ways that no Pip-Boy map can replace.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Heal the tribe, maintain its traditions, and counsel the Chieftan. You are the keeper of what the tribe was and the guide toward what it might become. Your expertise makes you valuable to outsiders as well.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#d69b3d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Tribesperson[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] The everyday members of a wasteland tribe are living proof that post-war humanity can survive without pre-war infrastructure. They hunt, gather, craft, cultivate, and carry the weight of daily life. Their skills are often more practical and harder-won than those of vault dwellers who have never once wondered where their food came from.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Keep the tribe alive. Hunt, gather, farm, and craft. Your labor is the foundation that every Chieftan's decision rests on. Without you, there is no tribe.
</Box>

## Relations

Tribal relations with other factions are complex and vary by Chieftan decision. Historically, tribes have traded with townspeople and cautiously engaged with caravans. The Brotherhood has a mixed record with tribal groups — some commanders see value in recruiting strong warriors, while others view tribals with open suspicion or hostility.
</Document>
