<Document>
# New California Republic (NCR)

## Core Mission

"To free the oppressed and restore the ideals of the Republic through unconventional warfare. In the absence of higher command, we will train local militias, build indigenous resistance, and conduct surgical strikes against authoritarian threats to secure this sector."

## Roleplay Directive

This NCR group shouldn't just charge into battle. They are stranded and lack reinforcements. Their roleplay should focus on winning hearts and minds, recruiting locals to fight for them, gathering intelligence, and fighting a guerrilla war against the Legion and the Brotherhood.

## Chain of Command

### Officers

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Captain[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Command the NCR's local detachment. All military and diplomatic decisions run through you. Balance force, political dealings, and the Republic's interests — your choices determine whether the NCR gains a foothold in Wendover or retreats in failure.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Lieutenant[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Second-in-command. Support the Captain, manage day-to-day operations, and step into command if the Captain is unavailable. You are the bridge between officer intent and the NCOs who execute it.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Medical Doctor[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Senior medical officer attached to the NCR detachment. Keep soldiers combat-capable, treat civilian allies to build goodwill, and advise command on medical threats. Your skills are a diplomatic asset as much as a survival one.
</Box>

### Non-Commissioned Officers

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Sergeant First Class[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Senior NCO of the detachment. You translate officer intent into enlisted action — enforcing discipline, managing formation readiness, and carrying the load between command and the soldiers who carry out its orders.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Staff Sergeant[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Senior squad leader. Lead your troops in the field, coordinate with the Sergeant First Class, and handle the mid-level decisions that keep small-unit operations running. You have enough rank to make things happen without waiting for permission.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Sergeant[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Squad leader. Know your soldiers, execute the Staff Sergeant's direction, and make the right call when there is no time to ask. NCR troopers live or die by Sergeant-level judgment.
</Box>

### Enlisted

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Specialist[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Trained specialist serving in combat, engineering, or medical roles as needed. Pick your loadout to match the mission — whether that means holding the line with heavy weapons, building fortifications, or keeping soldiers alive in the field. Your versatility is what makes the NCR work.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Private First Class[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Experienced private. You have proven you can be relied on — better gear, slightly more latitude, a little more trust from the NCOs above you. Hold the line and keep moving up.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Private[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Standard soldier. Enforce NCR authority, protect personnel and assets, and carry out orders. The politics are above your grade — your job is to be where you are told and do it well.
</Box>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Recruit[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Newest enlistee. You are at the bottom of a very long ladder. Follow orders, learn the ropes, and avoid getting yourself or your squadmates killed. Everything else comes later.
</Box>

### Special

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Prisoner[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Held in NCR custody pending processing or release. What happens to you next depends on what you did, who is in command, and how cooperative you decide to be.
</Box>
</Document>
