<Document>
# Factions

Fallout 14 features a large number of roles and factions, some of which are more important and widespread than others:

## Major factions

### NCR
The revived government of the USA, the NCR is a civilized military democracy seeking to spread its ideals across the Wasteland. Their role here is to try to convince the town residents to join the NCR.

### Town Residents
Town residents are locals who are the center of civilization, simply trying to survive and improve their lives through farming, scavenging, and trade.

Larger factions have recently taken notice of the town, and it is up to the mayor how to lead their people under this new external pressure.

### Tribes
Local tribes play an important role in maintaining the balance of the local ecology. They are led by a tribal chieftan who defines the culture, ideals, and attitude of the tribe.
Whether traditional or progressive thinking, passive or aggressive, isolationist or willing to join the town and trade.

### Vault Dwellers
Local vault dwellers are mostly unknown to surface inhabitants. The vault's location has largely been lost to time. Vault dwellers live in harmony underground, waiting for the day the door might open.
The vault is led by an Overseer who, unbeknownst to residents, may have a goal or experiment to carry out. A key component in the vault can also fail at any moment, forcing them to react and adapt, possibly opening the door for help.

### Caravan Company
The caravan company is the main source of new resources and equipment in the Wasteland. They have established supply routes for long-distance trade, which is especially useful when local resources begin to run out.
The CC is a non-aggressive faction. They can store valuables in their depots and can strike a deal with the NCR for additional protection in exchange for supply routes.
If the CC is lost or destroyed, the railway supply station will cease to function.

### Washington Brotherhood of Steel
The Washington Brotherhood of Steel is a splinter branch of the Brotherhood of Steel, descended from a Midwest Brotherhood expedition that lost contact. They are the most formidable local force in our Wasteland and are a faction of purists who hate any mutations.

They have technological goals and are known for kidnapping people. They try to act discreetly but have enormous firepower if they need to use it.

### Midwest Brotherhood of Steel
The Midwest Brotherhood of Steel is another splinter organization from the original Brotherhood. They have different values and are known for recruiting locals into the faction to achieve their goals, including tribes, ghouls, and mutants.

In this setting, the Midwest Brotherhood of Steel is scouting the area for their original lost patrols, which later became the Washington Brotherhood of Steel. They conduct reconnaissance, stay in the shadows, and avoid confrontation.

### Caesar's Legion
Caesar's Legion is an autocratic, traditionalist, imperialist slaveholding society and a totalitarian dictatorship based on the ideals of the Roman Empire.

Founded by Caesar the Great, they seek to conquer the Wasteland and spread their power, however due to the influence of other factions they are forced to act more cautiously to avoid unnecessary conflicts.
</Document>
